# **HOWARD LUAN**

Howard@Luan.contact | https://www.linkedin.com/in/howardluan/ | Halifax, NS

## **SUMMARY**

Knowledgeable and professional graduates in Technical Support role. Provided technical support and upgraded technological equipment for over 50 staff. Experience in explaining technical terms to non-technical users. Planned and created user documentation, such as manual, self-troubleshooting guides, system recommendation. Highly efficient, attention to detail with strong problem-solving, customer service and communication.

## **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Computer Science, Co-op, Minor in Entrepreneurship & Innovation

Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia

Class of 2022

20 Weeks Cyber Security Program

Digital Nova Scotia Skill for Hire Atlantic

2024

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Certificate in Communication Technologies & Cyber Security Dalhousie University (2022)
- Certificate in Web & Mobile Development Dalhousie University (2022)
- Certificate in Technical Support Fundamentals Google (2022)
- Certified in Cybersecurity (CC) and ISC2 Member ISC2 (2024)

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Guest Services Agent**

April 2023 – Present

#### **Future Inns Halifax Hotel & Conferences Centre**

- Assisted guests in booking, modifying, and cancelling their reservations promptly.
- Welcomed guests and assisted in checking them in, helping move luggage and guiding guests as needed.
- Answered inquiries and provided information clearly and efficiently, including billing issues, information of immediate area, services, attractions, and events to guests.
- Completed transactions while handling money responsibly and counting out change accurately to prevent errors.
- Acted as relief Sales Manager, managing group sales and on-site meeting rooms by drafting contracts, coordinating with catering departments, ensuring high levels of customer satisfaction by addressing inquiries promptly, resolving issues effectively, and maintaining open communication with clients.

#### **Program Facilitator**

January 2021 – April 2024

#### **Code Ninjas Halifax**

- Explained JavaScript, Lua, C# code concepts and algorithms to kids, from six to fourteen, helping them understand the concepts better and solve their problems in their games.
- Led and instructed multiple Roblox, Scratch and YouTube camps. Tasks include planning the curriculum, presenting, explaining, and helping participants with their content. Resulted in the increasing of returning kids to the programs.
- Created a Unity game used for promotions purpose and entertainment for kids, based on pre-developed characters and functions, as a motivation for kids to learn more and enjoy their time in the class.
- Welcomed and checked in kids to the class, provided customer service to parents and introduced the program to first-time parents and kids. Resulted in boosting the sign-up rate for the organization.

Howard Luan (902) 981-8090 Howard@Luan.contact

# **Desktop Support Technician**

#### **Dalhousie University**

May 2022 – Dec 2022

- Installed, upgraded, tested, and optimized computer systems for over 50 offices, including laptops, printers, docking stations, cable organizations, and ensured their secure operation.
- Prepared, configurated, and installed new equipment for new employees, and guided the employees with the on-boarding process. Resulted in less technical support tickets from new employees.
- Provided first-tier support for desktop, hardware, printer, and network issues and resolved software problems for desktop and portable devices.
- Troubleshot and resolved hardware, software, and driver problems both onsite and remotely for over 50 staff members, ensuring minimal disruption to users' work. Received compliments from manager and employees for the knowledge and patience working with the employees.

# **Technical Operational Assistant**

January 2022 – March 2022

# **Dalhousie University**

- Conducted surveys among unit staff to identify technical skill gaps and system issues, and developed formal self-service training resources, such as troubleshooting tips, step-by-step guides for common issues experienced by staff and frequently asked questions document for internal staff. Received compliments from supervisors and colleagues for the detail and format.
- Planned, installed, upgraded, tested technology equipment for staff, including laptops, printers, docking stations, cable organizations. Completed the implementation ahead of schedule by one week.
- Provided in-person and remote technical support for staff having issues with new equipment, including software, hardware, cables, and docks. Received compliments from directors and employees for the knowledge and patience in solving technical issues.

## myDal User Experience Coordinator

September 2021 – December 2021

## **Dalhousie University**

- Performed, reviewed, and reported on the usability of the internal department site and provided recommendations to improve the user experience for employees. Resulted in the implementation of the recommended report.
- Planned, drafted, and created user documentation for staff to perform usability testing for their site.

  Document included recruiting participants, scripting for a usability test, what to perform during usability test.

  Accepted by supervisor and later distributed for internal use.
- Reviewed, summarized, and reported on various usability testing tools and provided recommendation to the organization. Saved the subscription fees on usability testing tools.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Microsoft 365 E5 Developer

- Implemented and maintained the Microsoft 365 environment, including Outlook email system, user management, security, and compliance of the environment.
- Managed user accounts, permissions, and access to ensure secure and efficient operations.
- Implemented and monitored policies for threat protection, including anti-spam, anti-phishing, and anti-malware, and information protection, including data loss prevention, encryption, and information classification.
- Created and tested apps and automatic workflows using PowerApps and Power Automate.